Stephen Johnston

PROFILE

I am a full-stack software developer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems and an enthusiasm for continuous learning and improvement. I have multiple years of experience in the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, as well as experience with various frameworks and AWS.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Co-Creator, *Herald* □

2023 – present

Herald is an observability solution that allows software developers to conveniently collect and explore telemetry data, including logs, traces, and metrics, through a single, user-friendly interface

- Engineered the automatic provisioning and deployment of a data pipeline for the collection, processing, storage, and visualization of logs, traces, and metrics data
- Created a CLI tool to facilitate set-up, configuration, deployment, and tear-down of the ELK stack—Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana—on AWS
- Automated cloud deployment of multiple Elasticsearch and Logstash clusters, and a single node of Kibana using AWS CDK
- Architected the generation and storage of certificates to ensure secure communication of pipeline components using TLS encryption
- Containerized components of pipeline infrastructure with appropriate dependencies and runtime environments using AWS ECS
- Engineered service discovery using AWS Cloud Map to ensure successful communication among infrastructure components
- Implemented auto-scaling of Elasticsearch cluster based on a CPU-utilization target
- Authored comprehensive case study discussing the use case, design decisions, and implementation challenges experienced when building Herald
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 developers across Canada and the U.S. using agile workflow

Software Developer, *Self-employed*

2019 - 2023

- PanicBin tool for inspecting and debugging webhooks (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, React)
- BuyPal e-commerce shopping-cart app (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, React)
- Taskify productivity app for tracking and managing habits and tasks (Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Handlebars)

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, Ruby, Go, SQL, React, Express, Sinatra, Handlebars, jQuery, Jest, HTML/CSS

Other Technologies

Node.js, Git/Github, Docker, Nginx, MongoDB, HTTP, Bash, RESTful APIs, Linux, postgreSQL, ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana)

Cloud

AWS (CDK, EC2, ECS, EFS, IAM, Lambda, CloudMap, CloudWatch, Fargate), Digital Ocean Droplets, Heroku, Fly.io

EDUCATION

Saint Mary's University, *Bachelor of Commerce (Bcom), Marketing* Member of the Men's Varsity Hockey Team

2011 - 2016

NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS